Guide to the Donald Jay Grout papers,1929-2002.
Grout, Donald Jay papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Donald Jay Grout papers, 1929-2002.
14-20-998
Donald Jay. Grout
46.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Photographs, Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes professional correspondence and applications and recommendations for grants and university positions. Also, personal correspondence with his parents while studying in Europe and teaching at Mills College and with a friend, Jonathan Schiller; worksheets, photographs and galley proofs for A HISTORY OF WESTERN MUSIC and both editions of A SHORT HISTORY OF OPERA; notes and notebooks on "Early Opèra Comique" and others, his dissertation manuscript; a manuscript on West Indian Music; lecture notes; musical tapes; annotated programs; and a typescript of an article "How to Tell Good Music from Bad;" alphabetical correspondence file, correspondence with W. W. Norton.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Donald Jay Grout was a professor of musicology at Cornell, where he held the Given Foundation Chair of Musicology from 1962-1970. Grout is best known for his widely used textbook A History of Western Music. An expert in opera, he also wrote A Short History of Opera and organized the first published editions of several operas by Alessandro Scarlatti. Grout received his AB in philosophy from Syracuse University in 1923 before matriculating at Harvard. After studies in Europe with Gérold, Prod'homme and R.M. Haas, he received his PhD from Harvard in 1939, and was appointed associate professor at the University of Texas in 1942. In 1945, Grout became professor at Cornell University. He remained at Cornell until his retirement, with the exception of visiting professorships at Carleton College (1955), the University of Utrecht (1959–60) and the University of California at Berkeley (1975–6). Grout served as president of the American Musicological Society (1952–4; 1960–62), and was the recipient of many awards, including Fulbright and Guggenheim research fellowships (Italy, 1951–2), Fulbright fellowships (Utrecht, 1959–60; Belgium, 1965–6), the Archibald Thompson Davison Medal for Musicology (1962), and the George Arents Pioneer Medal from Syracuse University (1965).
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes professional correspondence with William W. Austin, Andrea della Corte, Archibald Davison, D. Keith Falkner, Scott Goldthwaite, Otto Kinkeldey, Jan LaRue, Zofia Lissa, Rey Longyear, Rosamond McGuinness, Arthur Mendel, A. Tillman Merritt, Robert U. Nelson, Nino Pirrotta, Eduard Reeser, Walter Rubsamen, Leo Schrade, Denis Stevens, Oliver Strunk, Peter Gram Swing, Robert Tangeman, Frederic Tillotson, Henry Woodward, G. Wallace Woodworth, and Columbia University Press; and applications and recommendations for grants and university positions. Also, personal correspondence with his parents while studying in Europe and teaching at Mills College (1933-1936) and with a friend and former student, Jonathan Schiller (1943-1982); worksheets, photographs and galley proofs for History of Western Music and both editions of A Short History of the Opera; notes and notebooks on "Early Opèra Comique" (ca.1936-1941), "Molière's Comèdie-Ballets" (ca.1937-1942), "Gherardi's Music" (1939), and "Parodies in Opèra Comique" (1939); his dissertation manuscript (1939); a manuscript on West Indian Music (1942); lecture notes; musical tapes; annotated programs; and a typescript of an article "How to Tell Good Music from Bad" (1955) with comment by William W. Austin; alphabetical correspondence file, correspondence with W. W. Norton; and correspondence relating to A Short History of the Opera and to The Operas of Alessandro Scarlatti.
"Grout Films Index" (3 ring binders) listing microfilms in the Music Library collected by Grout; "Grout Films Index Supplement" (folder); "Scarlatti Catalog," compiled by Michael Keller under the guidance of Donald J. Grout, cataloging the Scarlatti materials collected by Grout and held in the Music Library; and Grout address book containing information about libraries throughout Europe and a brief listing of some of the microfilms.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Austin, William W., 1920-2000; Blume, Friedrich, 1893-1975.; Davison, Archibald T.(Archibald Thompson), 1883-1961.; Della Corte, Andrea, 1883-1968.; Eggebrecht, Hans Heinrich.; Falkner, Keith, 1900-1994; Goldthwaite, Scott, 1901-1981.; Grout, Donald Jay.; Kinkeldey, Otto, 1878-1966.; Lang, Paul Henry, 1901-1991.; LaRue, Jan, 1918-2004.; Lissa, Zofia.; Longyear, Rey M.(Rey Morgan), 1930-1995.; McGuinness, Rosamond "Corky", 1929-2012.; Mendel, Arthur, 1905-1979.; Merritt, A. Tillman(Arthur Tillman), 1902-1998.; Nelson, Robert U.(Robert Uriel), 1902-1995.; Nettl, Bruno, 1930-; Pirrotta, Nino., 1908-1998.; Reeser, Eduard, 1908-2002.; Rubsamen, Walter H.(Walter Howard), 1911-1973.; Scarlatti, Alessandro, 1660-1725.; Schiller, Jonathan.; Schrade, Leo, 1903-1964.; Stevens, Denis, 1922-2004.; Strunk, W. Oliver(William Oliver), 1901-1980.; Swing, Peter Gram.; Tangeman, Roberts.; Tillotson, Frederic Erle Thornlay.; Woodward, Henry L.(Henry Lynde), 1908-; Woodworth, G. Wallace.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University.Dept. of Music.
Subjects:
Music--Instruction and study.; Opera.; Operas.; Musicians--United States.; Authors, American.; College teachers--United States.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Boxes 1-10, 51-55
Correspondence 1929-1936 Largely personal, primarily related to Grout's early career in music, his doctoral research in Europe, and his teaching at Mills College.
Correspondence 1940-1945 Mainly related to Grout's career at Harvard and the University of Texas.
Correspondence 1950-1967 Related to Grout's career at Cornell.
Correspondence 1942-1958 With Columbia University Press.
Correspondence 1961-1980 With individuals.
Correspondence 1961-1974 Related to International Musicological Society (1%) and International Music Librarians Association (IMLA).
Correspondence 1970-1974 Related to International Josquin Festival Conference.
Correspondence 1958-1976 Related to Repertoire International des Sources Musicales (RISM) (Inventory of Musical Sources).
Correspondence 1966-1970 Related to Utrecht (Institute voor muziekwetenschap der rijksuniversiteit te Utrecht) (Institute of Musicology).
Correspondence 1926-2002 Additional Correspondence. Primarily from period of Grout's retirement (1970-1987)and following his death
Series II. Short History of Opera
Boxes 10-14, 26-28
Correspondence Related to first and second editions
Correspondence With Columbia University Press
Notes and other items Related to opera, opéra comique, the music of Gherardi, Molière's comedie-ballets, vaudevilles, parodies, musical examples, and a manuscript copy of Grout's doctoral thesis on opéra comique.
Work sheets for first edition
Work sheets for second edition
Printer's copy and material related to the publications
Proofread copy with changes
Partial printed copy of revised edition
Galleys
Bibliography cards
Series III. History of Western Music
Boxes 14-17, 29-42
Work sheets
Partial copy with revision tabs
Printer's copy
Miscellaneous examples of music systems, etc.
Multilith copy
Material related to the second (1973) and third (1980) editions Including notes, opinions, and comments.
Galleys
Series IV. The Operas of Alessandro Scarlatti
Boxes 18-24, 56-57, 59-75
Eraclea Vol. I of The Operas of Alessandro Scarlatti.
Marco Attilio Regolo Vol. II of The Operas of Alessandro Scarlatti.
Griselda Vol. III of The Operas of Alessandro Scarlatti.
The Faithful Princess Vol. IV of The Operas of Alessandro Scarlatti.
Massimo Pupieno Vol. V of The Operas of Alessandro Scarlatti.
La caduta de'Decemviri Vol. VI of The Operas of Alessandro Scarlatti.
Unpublished manuscript scores, libretti and notes.
Other material Related to all volumes of The Operas of Alessandro Scarlatti.
Introduction to the Operas of Alessandro Scarlatti
Berkeley Lectures 1977-1978 On the Operas of Alessandro Scarlatti
The Operas of Alessandro Scarlatti Editorial Correspondence
Series V. Reviews, articles, lectures, and papers
Boxes 24, 25, 46, 49, 50
Series VI. Norton Historical Anthology of Music (NOHAM) Edited by Claude V. Paliska.
Box 25
Series VII. Photographs
Boxes 44, 81-82
Short History of Opera
Scarlatti operas
Other photographs
Series VIII. Collected concert and opera programs
Box 45
Series IX. Wire and tape recordings
Box 47
Series X. PhD. Dissertation, "The Origins of the Opera Comique"
Box 48
Series XI. Inventories of Grout's Score Collection and Miscellaneous Copies of Manuscript Scores
Boxes 58,75-77, 80
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Correspondence - Early Career, 1929-1936
    Largely personal, primarily related to Grout's early career in music, his doctoral research in Europe, and his teaching at Mills College.
    - Correspondence, December 1929 - December 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, January - July 1934 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, August - December 1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, January - December 1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, January - October 1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Harvard and Texas, 1940-1945
    Mainly related to Grout's career at Harvard and the University of Texas.
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, January - February 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, March - May 1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, June - December 1943 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, January - April 1944 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, May - June 1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, July - August 1944 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, September 1944, undated 1944, 1945, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Cornell, 1950-1967
    Related to Grout's career at Cornell.
    - Correspondence A, 1954-1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence A, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence A, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence A, 1961 - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence B, 1953 - 1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence B, 1958 - 1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence B, 1960 - 1961 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence B, 1962 - 1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence B, 1965 - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence C, 1953 - 1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence C, 1959 - 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence C, 1961 - 1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence C, 1963 - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence Davison, 1961 - 1964, 1961 - 1964 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Davison (articles) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence D, 1952 - 1957 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence D, 1958 - 1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence D, 1963 - 1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence E, 1956 - 1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence F, 1953 - 1958 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence F, 1959 - 1962 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence F, 1963 - 1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence G, 1953 - 1957 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence G, 1958 - 1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence G, 1964 - 1967 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence H, 1953 - 1956 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence H, 1957 - 1959 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence H, 1960 - 1963 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence H, 1964 - 1967 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence I, 1955 - 1964 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence J, 1953 - 1965 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence K, 1951 - 1958 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence K, 1959 - 1962 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence K, 1963 - 1967 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence Longyear, 1958 - 1967 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence L, 1953 - 1957 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence L, 1958 - 1960 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence L, 1961 - 1962 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence L, 1963 - 1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence L, 1965 - 1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence M, 1953 - 1956 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence M, 1957 - 1961 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence M, 1962 - 1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence Mc, 1953 - 1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence N, O, 1953 - 1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence P, 1953 - 1960 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence P, 1961 - 1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence R, 1953 - 1958 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence R, 1959 - 1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence S, 1950 - 1955 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence S, 1956 - 1958 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence S, 1959 - 1960 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence S, 1961 - 1962 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence S, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence S, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence S, 1965 - 1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence T, 1953 - 1958 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence T, 1959 - 1967 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence U, 1953 - 1963 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence V, 1953 - 1957 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence W, 1953 - 1958 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence W, 1959 - 1962 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence W, 1963 - 1967 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence X, Y, Z, 1953 - 1961 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Columbia University Press, 1942-1958
    With Columbia University Press.
    - Correspondence, 1942 - 1945 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1946 - 1947 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1947 - 1951 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1951 - 1958 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Individuals, 1961-1980
    - Correspondence B miscellaneous, 1966 - 1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Blume, Friedrich (mostly RISM), 1964 - March 1964 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Blume, April - December 1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Blume, 1965 - 1966 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Blume, 1967 - 1968 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Blume, 1969 - 1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Blume (also Mrs. Christel Blume), 1973 - 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Brook, Barry S. (RILM), 1965 - 1967 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Chase, Gilbert (RISM), 1963 - 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Crain, Gordon Ferris, 1973 - 1974 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Cvetko, Dragotin, 1965 - 1967 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Evans, Edward G. Jr, 1967 - 1968 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Fedorov, M. Vladimir, 1961 - 1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Fischer, Kurt von (IMS), 1961 - 1970 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Gehmacher, Friedrich (Mozart Foundation), 1970 - 1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Henle G. (in re Martin Bente), 1969 - 1974 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Hsu, John, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Hucke, Helmut, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Lenaerts, René B., 1967 - 1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Lissa, Zofia, 1963 - 1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Longyear, Rey Morgan, 1967 - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Longyear, 1972 - 1975 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Longyear, 1976 - 1977 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Mohr, Ernst, 1967 - 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Mozarteum I, 1966 - 1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Mozarteum II, 1973 - 1975 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Rollin, Robert Leon, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Sedlin, Murry, 1966 - 1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Strunk, Oliver, 1967 - 1980 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Tangeman, Oliver, 1967 - 1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Tinayre, Yves, 1968 - 1976 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Westrup, Jack, 1968 - 1975 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Wiora, Walter Festschrift, 1965 - 1967 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Woodward, Henry, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence - International Musicological Society and International Music Librarians Association, 1961-1974
    Related to International Musicological Society (IMS) and International Music Librarians Association (IMLA).
    - A.I.B.M. (Association internationale des bibliothèques musicales), 1961 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - USSR, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Foundations (general information), 1961 - 1962 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Acta, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - General memoranda, committee lists, statutes, 1961 - 1965 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Mohr, 1961 - 1963 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Mohr, 1964 - 1969 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Martha Baird Rockefeller Fund for Music, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Vaughan, Denis, 1962 - 1965 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Gulbenkian Foundation, Inc., 1962 - 1967 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - DDR (Deutsche Demokratische Republik), 1964 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Vogl-Garret Request, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Communiqués and circular letters, 1965 - 1969 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Ljubljana, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Dr. M. Burckhardt, treasurer, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Mailing, March 24, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Mailing, May 30, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Address List, 1966 - 1967 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Basel (IMS Directorium), 1969 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Minutes and miscellaneous, 1972 - 1974 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence - International Josquin Festival Conference, 1970-1974
    Related to International Josquin Festival Conference.
    - Correspondence, December 1969 - May 1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, June - December 1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, January - April 1971 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, May - June 1971 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, July - October 1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Expenses and accounts, 1971 - 1974 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Expenses and accounts, 1971 - 1974 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Répertoire International des Sources Musicales, 1958-1976
    Related to Répertoire International des Sources Musicales (RISM) (Inventory of Musical Sources).
    - Ford Foundation (closed file of early correspondence before September 1962), 1962 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Ford Foundation, September - August 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Ford Foundation, September - August 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Ford Foundation, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Ford Foundation, 1966 - February 1969 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - RISM, 1965 - 1976 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - RISM, 1977 - 1978 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Foundations, 1969, 1958, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1970 - 1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1974 - 1976 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Utrecht, 1966-1970
    Related to Utrecht (Institute voor muziekwetenschap der rijksuniversiteit te Utrecht) (Institute of Musicology).
    - Correspondence, 1966 - 1969 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1960 - 1970 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Primarily from period of Grout's retirement (1970-1987)and following his death
    - Harold Samuel correspondence, 1956-1966 (Box 51)
    - A miscellaneous, 1968-1971 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Abert, Anna Amalie, 1969-1977 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Abraham, Gerald, 1968-1986 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - A. M. S. 50, 1984-1986 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1987 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Amerman, George and Gladys, 1972-1990 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Archibald, R. Bruce, 1971-1981 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Austin, W. W., 1971-1981 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - B misc. correspondence, 1985 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Articles and Correspondence re. J.S. Bach, 1985 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Badura-Skoda, Eva, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Badura-Skoda, Eva, 1968-1976 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Bärenreiter-Verlag correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Bärenreiter-Verlag receipts, 1951-1966 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Bärenreiter and Neuwerk, 1978-1982 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Barker, Nicholas, 1972-1983 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Bartha, Dénes, 1967-1980 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Becker, Heinz, 1968-1969 (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - Bergsagel, John, 1970-1982 (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - Berkeley, 1975-1976 (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - Berlin lecture on Ethnomusicology, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - Birthday letter (from K.D. Hartzell), 1983 (Box 52, Folder 21)
    - Blume, Christel (Box 52, Folder 22)
    - Blume, Friedrich, `976-1990 (Box 52, Folder 23)
    - Boatwright, Howard and Helen, 1987-1990 (Box 52, Folder 24)
    - Bonner, Walter and Jo, 1982-1986 (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - Boyden, David, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - Briant, John, 1971-1975 (Box 52, Folder 27)
    - British Academy, 1978 (Box 52, Folder 28)
    - Brook, Barry, 1980-1981 (Box 52, Folder 29)
    - Brown, Howard, 1970-1978 (Box 52, Folder 30)
    - Buelow, George, 1968-1981 (Box 52, Folder 31)
    - C misc. correspondence, 1968-1977 (Box 52, Folder 32)
    - Cabral, Edward, 1982 (Box 52, Folder 33)
    - Campbell, William, 1968-1987 (Box 52, Folder 34)
    - Carapetyan, Armen, 1967-1988 (Box 52, Folder 35)
    - Carruth, Jack, 1969-1972 (Box 52, Folder 36)
    - Century Association, NYC, 1969-1976 (Box 52, Folder 37)
    - Chambure, Thibault, 1967-1968 (Box 52, Folder 38)
    - Chen Zong-gun, Peking, China, 1988 (Box 52, Folder 39)
    - Chihara, Paul, 1969-1974 (Box 52, Folder 40)
    - China Missions, 1987-1988 (Box 52, Folder 41)
    - Christakis, Chris, 1974-1976 (Box 52, Folder 42)
    - Clark, David E., 1984 (Box 52, Folder 43)
    - Colas, Roger and Marguerite, 1968-1990 (Box 52, Folder 44)
    - Commanday, Robert, 1982-1987 (Box 52, Folder 45)
    - Cooper, Jeff, 1978-1981 (Box 52, Folder 46)
    - Cornell, correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 52, Folder 47)
    - Cornell correspondence, 1968-1978 (Box 52, Folder 48)
    - Cornell Music Library and Olin Library - gifts, 1981-1988 (Box 52, Folder 49)
    - Cox, Sidney, 1968-1980 (Box 52, Folder 50)
    - Crain, Gordon F., 1973-1980 (Box 52, Folder 51)
    - Crossman Jewelers, Auburn, 1978 (Box 52, Folder 52)
    - Cvetko, Dragotin, 1967-1976 (Box 52, Folder 53)
    - D misc. correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box 52, Folder 54)
    - Dent review, 1977 (Box 52, Folder 55)
    - Donington, Robert, 1967-1968 (Box 52, Folder 56)
    - Droppers, Joanne P., 1974-1987 (Box 52, Folder 57)
    - Duncan, Tim and Sharyn, 1982-1987 (Box 52, Folder 58)
    - E misc. correspondence, 1966-1977 (Box 52, Folder 59)
    - Eastman School of Music Visiting Committee, 1977-1979 (Box 52, Folder 60)
    - Elliott, Charles H. (Chuck), 1981-1985 (Box 52, Folder 61)
    - Emerson, John A., 1981 (Box 52, Folder 62)
    - Erickson-Bloch, Susan, 1971-1982 (Box 52, Folder 63)
    - F misc. correspondence, 1970-1984 (Box 52, Folder 64)
    - Faculty research grant, 1965-1970 (Box 52, Folder 65)
    - Falkner, Keith, 1968-1991 (Box 52, Folder 66)
    - Falkner, Christabel and Keith, 1978-1990 (Box 52, Folder 67)
    - Flaccovio, S.F., 1978-1990 (Box 52, Folder 68)
    - Fellerer, Karl Gustav, 1982 (Box 52, Folder 69)
    - Forbes, Elliot, 1973-1981 (Box 52, Folder 70)
    - Foreign Musicological Societies, 1981-1987 (Box 52, Folder 71)
    - Fotios, [Andreaopoulos] (Athens), 1980 (Box 52, Folder 72)
    - Freeman, Robert, 1982-1986 (Box 52, Folder 73)
    - Freeman, Robert, 1967-1979 (Box 52, Folder 74)
    - French, Richard F., 1973-1987 (Box 52, Folder 75)
    - Fulbright Alumni Association, correspondence and newsletters (Box 52, Folder 76)
    - G. misc. correspondence, 1969-1979 (Box 52, Folder 77)
    - Galkin, Elliot, 1975-1991 (Box 52, Folder 78)
    - Galkin Article on Grout, 1977-1980 (Box 52, Folder 79)
    - Gianturco, Carolyn, 1974-1978 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Griffin, Thomas E., 1979 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Grout, Donald Jay (articles, lectures), 1972 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Grout, Donald Jay (letters to Rosamond "Corky" McGuinness), 1972 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Grove Dictionary, 1983 (Box 53, Folder 5)